Inventory of the Papers of Lewis Preston Collins
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
Inventory of the Papers of Lewis Preston Collins
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
MSS 85-6
21 boxes (9.1 linear feet)
Lewis Preston ("Pat") Collins was born in Lynchburg, Virginia, in 1896. After attending Washington and Lee University and serving in World War I, he obtained a law degree from Yale University and began practicing law in the town of Marion, located in southwest Virginia. His law practice papers demonstrate his influence as a lawyer and Democratic politician in a small Virginia town during the 1930s. Although he often represented "outside" interests such as the State Highway Department, the Norfolk and Western Railway, and the Appalachian Electric Power Company, he also managed to look out for the interests of the community. Collins represented his district in the Virginia General Assembly from 1936 until 1946, and served as Lieutenant Governor under Governors William M. Tucka and John S. Battle.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
Lewis Preston ("Pat") Collins was born in Lynchburg, Virginia, in 1896. He was educated in the public schools of Marion, Virginia and attended Washington and Lee University until he was called to serve in World War I. In 1919 he began the study of law at Yale University and was awarded the LL.B. in 1922, the same year that he received his B.A. from Washington and Lee. Collins was admitted to the Virginia Bar in July of 1922 and immediately set up his law practice in the town of Marion. As his practice grew, he also became active in local civic organizations and politics, eventually becoming district chairman of the Democratic Party.
Marion, the Smyth County seat, is located in southwest Virginia about forty miles northeast of Bristol and a hundred miles southwest of Roanoke. Collins carried on a civil practice which primarily served people in Smyth and the adjacent counties of Washington and Wythe. Early in his career he represented individuals in family, probate and real estate matters and served as "committee" for veterans with mental or emotional problems in order that they could receive their Veterans' Administration benefits. In 1933 when the Federal Home Owners' Loan Act established the Home Owners' Loan Corporation, Collins served as local counsel and handled closings for the Corporation. A year later he was appointed Commissioner of Accounts of the Circuit Court of Smyth County and became responsible for the settlement of accounts when wills were probated in that court. Toward the end of the 1930's Collins began to make investigations, settle claims and handle lawsuits for the Virginia Auto Mutual, Pennsylvania, and State Farm insurance companies. When the State Highway Department began planning to build Route 11 through his area of the state, he represented the department in disputes over the value of land and handled the settlements of payment for land claimed for the highway. Soon thereafter he began to handle similar cases for the Norfolk and Western Railway, which was running a track parallel to the new highway. Collins' other corporate clients included the Kroger Grocery and Baking Company, the town of Saltville, the Appalachian Electric Power Company, the Saltville plant of the Mathieson Alkali Works, and the Marion National Bank. He also represented one of the defendants in an antitrust case brought by an independent theatre owner against several competitors and a number of the major film companies.
While Collins represented several "outside" interests in his practice, he also managed to look out for the interests of the community and used his many contacts when asked to do so. His law practice papers demonstrate the influence of a lawyer/Democratic politician in a small Virginia town during the 1930's. Collins was the delegate from his district to the Virginia General Assembly from 1936 until 1946 when he was elected Lieutenant Governor. After serving a term under Governor William M. Tuck, Collins ran and won again, this time to serve with Governor John S. Battle. However, Collins' promising political career was cut short by his untimely death at the age of 56.
Organization
For reasons that have not been discerned, these law office files were maintained in three sets, and so they are now arranged in three series although none is very long. The entire collection fills 21 boxes (9.1 linear feet) and spans 1924 to 1952, with most of the papers concentrated in the years 1933 to 1942.
Series I in Boxes 1 - 12 contains case files for the State Highway Department, Norfolk and Western Railway, Virginia Auto Mutual Insurance, Appalachian Electric Power, and other corporations Collins represented including the theatre owner (Byers Theatre v. Murphy). This series also has his Commissioner of Accounts reports and files for individual private clients. These records covering 1933-42 were in folders numbered 1 to 217, although some of that number are missing; the numerical order has been retained.
Series II in Boxes 12 - 16 covers the same time period and were numbered (1 - 372 with many gaps) in the law office. This numerical arrangement is also roughly chronological. Many of these files contain one or two pieces of correspondence about relatively simple matters, although the contents of some of them relate to cases in the other series. Because Collins' various groupings for his files have been preserved, researchers will benefit from a careful reading of the box list when trying to follow a particular case.
Finally, Series III in Boxes 16 - 21 contains files that were in no particular order, so they have been arranged alphabetically. The types of cases here are similar to those in Series I, but the predominant years are the mid-1920's and the later 1940's.
Additional Information
Separated Material
The Papers of Lewis Preston Collins were transferred to the Law Library from the Manuscripts Department of Alderman Library in 1985. These papers from Collins' law practice were donated to the University along with his personal and political papers, which have remained at Alderman in accordance with the wishes of the donor, Lewis Preston Collins III. The finding aid for the Collins Papers at Alderman is available in the Law Library upon request.
Contents List
- Folders Numbered 1-217:
  - [Virginia] Brosius: Loan, 1934-35 (Box 1)
  - Better Housing Institute, 1933 (Box 1)
  - [Charles A.] Cooley: Loan, 1934 (Box 1)
  - W.B. Crockett: Loan, 1933-34 (Box 1)
  - Hannah S. Cannon: Loan, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Commissioner of Accounts: Reports, 1934-37, -41, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Dale Cole (Home Owners' Loan Corporation), 1939 (Box 1)
  - Jacob L. Davidson: Loan, 1934-35 (Box 1)
  - John R. George: Loan, 1934 (Box 1)
  - Eugene A. Hyde: Abstract, 1934 (Box 1)
  - [Martha Brewer] Hackler: Loan, 1934 (Box 2)
  - Home Owners' Loan Corporation, 1933-35 (Box 2)
  - Highway Commission: F.J. Allen Right of Way, 1933 (Box 2)
  - Sam Henegar: Loan, 1934-35 (Box 2)
  - [George Lester] Hensley, 1937-38 (Box 2)
  - Dr. A.L. Jones, 1934 (Box 2)
  - Charles A. McVey, 1934 (Box 2)
  - [Charles G.] Miller: Loan, 1934 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous File, 1937-38 (Box 2)
  - Norfolk & Western Railway: W.V. Birchfield, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Martin v. Perkins, 1941 (Box 2)
  - [Rachel P.] Poore, 1935 (Box 2)
  - Mary G. Proctor, 1934-36 (Box 3)
  - [B. Scott] Sprinkle: Loan, 1934-36 (Box 3)
  - Shirley v. Thomas, 1934 (Box 3)
  - A.C. Snider, 1934-35 (Box 3)
  - Claude Sullivan: LPC Committee, 1927-32, 1935-38, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - State Highway v. C.V. Caudill, 1934 (Box 3)
  - State Highway v. Shanklin, 1934 (Box 3)
  - M.J. Shrader, 1933-34 (Box 3)
  - State Highway v. Gordon, 1934 (Box 4)
  - State Highway v. Sawyers, 1934 (Box 4)
  - Transfer from C.L. Collins to T. F. Cox, 1937 (Box 4)
  - U.S. v. Bishop, 1941 (Box 4)
  - C.A. Umbarger, 1933 (Box 4)
  - Virginia Auto Mutual Insurance Co. (VAMI): Cox, 1937-39 (Box 4)
  - VAMI: Meek, 1937 (Box 4)
  - VAMI: Wilder, 1937 (Box 4)
  - Virginia Lunch: ABC Hearing, 1937 (Box 4)
  - Walters on Property Abstract, 1934 (Box 4)
  - N.S. Wright & Co., 1933 (Box 4)
  - R.F. Taylor, 1934 (Box 4)
  - Wilkinson, 1936 (Box 4)
  - Airport, 1934 (Box 4)
  - Atlantic Life Insurance Co., 1938-39 (Box 4)
  - T.W. Buchanan Estate, 1933 (Box 4)
  - C.P. Blackwell, 1939-40 (Box 4)
  - Charles A. Vogt: LPC, Adm., 1933-34 (Box 4)
  - Brosius Loan Foreclosure, 1937 (Box 4)
  - Burch, 1936-37 (Box 4)
  - Lonnie Blevins, 1938 (Box 4)
  - Commissioner of Accounts, 1938-42 (Box 4)
  - Crockett Foreclosure, 1937-38 (Box 4)
  - Wimmer Loan, 1935 (Box 5)
  - Calfee, 1935-36 (Box 5)
  - Luigi Genga: LPC Committee, 1928-41 (Box 5)
  - F.M. Hughson, 1939-41 (Box 5)
  - Goolsby Estate, 1933-37 (Box 5)
  - Harwood Manufacturing Corp., 1938-39 (Box 5)
  - Maggie Lyons: Committee of Cortez E. Lyons, 1934-36 (Box 6)
  - Jackson v. Gilbert, 1939-40 (Box 6)
  - Francis C. Moore: LPC Committee, 1933-34 (Box 6)
  - Home Owners' Loan Corporation, 1940 (Box 6)
  - Callie Richardson Hutton, 1937-39 (Box 6)
  - Presley v. N. &. W. Railway, 1934-36 (Box 6)
  - Preston Estate, 1934 (Box 6)
  - Lulu Price, 1933 (Box 6)
  - Mrs. Will Johnston: Right of Way, 1936 (Box 6)
  - W.N. Richardson: ABC Board, 1940 (Box 6)
  - H. Boyd Staley: Insurance, 1939 (Box 6)
  - Seaver Estate, 1935-36 (Box 6)
  - John W. Lewis, 1939-40 (Box 6)
  - VAMI Co., 1938-40 (Box 6)
  - Iowa Steel and Iron Works v. J.F. Tilley & Co., 1932 (Box 7)
  - Keller v. Massachusetts Protective Association, 1931-32 (Box 7)
  - Russo v. Sayers, 1941 (Box 7)
  - Blevins v. Cole, 1933-35 (Box 7)
  - Buchanan v. Addington, 1934 (Box 7)
  - Byers Theatre v. Murphy, 1939-40 (Box 7)
  - Beverly v. Mauck, 1933 (Box 7)
  - Brickey v. Neff, 1932 (Box 7)
  - Bonham v. Keesee, 1940 (Box 7)
  - Coyner v. Lincoln Theatre, 1934-36 (Box 8)
  - Cassell v. Cassell, 1935 (Box 8)
  - Collins v. Moore, 1934 (Box 8)
  - Counts v. N. & W. Railway, 1935 (Box 8)
  - Collins v. Jones, 1933-34 (Box 8)
  - Commonwealth v. Ham, 1939 (Box 8)
  - Commonwealth v. Butler, 1940-41 (Box 8)
  - Commonwealth v. Sutherland, 1934 (Box 8)
  - Commonwealth v. Vaught, 1934 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Game and Inland Fisheries v. Watlington, 1935 (Box 8)
  - Hendry v. Ruggie, 1933 (Box 8)
  - Glover v. Walker, 1935-36 (Box 8)
  - Hendry v. Hendry, 1935-36 (Box 8)
  - Hendry Suits, 1936 (Box 8)
  - Hendricks v. Spurling, 1934-35 (Box 8)
  - Hull v. Sutherland, 1934-36 (Box 8)
  - Johnson v. Sheridan, 1935 (Box 8)
  - Shirley v. Phipps, 1933-34 (Box 8)
  - Mathieson Alkali v. Lona, 1941 (Box 8)
  - Jones v. Hinton, 1935 (Box 8)
  - Bonham v. Jones (see also Box 17), 1935 (Box 8)
  - Jones v. Hinton, 1936 (Box 8)
  - Klingstein v. Hotel Marion, 1935-36 (Box 9)
  - Marion National Bank v. Lindamood, 1939-40 (Box 9)
  - Litton v. Litton, 1927, -33 (Box 9)
  - Nelson v. Marion Bank Co., 1933-34 (Box 9)
  - Rosenbaum v. Kroger Grocery & Baking Co., 1937-39 (Box 9)
  - Southern Factories & Stores v. Lincoln Furniture, 1934 (Box 9)
  - State Highway: Rights of Way, 1936-38 (Box 9)
  - Saltville Water Works v. Chapman, 1936-37 (Box 9)
  - State Highway v. C.S. Wassum, 1936 (Box 9)
  - State Highway v. Ross, 1936 (Box 9)
  - State Highway v. Musser, 1936-37 (Box 9)
  - State Highway v. Hull, 1934-36 (Box 9)
  - State Highway v. Wheeler, 1936-37 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Cregger, 1936 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Copenhaver, 1937 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Bear, 1936 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Hutton, 1936 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Shuler, 1936 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Gammon, 1936 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Atkins, 1936 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Snavely, 1936 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Scott, 1936 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Musser, 1936 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Scott, 1936 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Cassell, 1936 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Calhoun, 1936 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Lutheran Church, 1936-37 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Harris, 1936 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Hounshell, 1936 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Riddle, 1937 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Groseclose, 1937 (Box 10)
  - Bonham v. Jones, 1942 (Box 10)
  - Hendry Estate, 1937-41 (Box 10)
  - A.F. Eller, 1940-41 (Box 10)
  - Dickinson v. N. & W. Railway, 1939-42 (Box 10)
  - Culbert Estate, 1940-42 (Box 10)
  - Commonwealth v. George A. Rheman Co., 1941 (Box 10)
  - Cox v. Marion Orange Crush Co. (Appeal), 1940-41 (Box 10)
  - O.P. Copenhaver, 1940-41 (Box 10)
  - Culbert Loan, 1940 (Box 10)
  - Chilhowie Realty Co., 1939 (Box 10)
  - Butler v. Blankenbeckler, 1940-41 (Box 10)
  - Betterton Coffee v. Wyatt, 1941 (Box 10)
  - Barrett v. N. & W. Railway, 1941 (Box 10)
  - J.B. Bonham, 1939 (Box 10)
  - H.L. Bonham Estate, 1934-39 (Box 10)
  - Bordwine v. Applachian Electric Power Co., 1940-41 (Box 10)
  - Appalachian Electric Power v. Saunders, 1941 (Box 10)
  - N. & W. Railway v. Hash, 1941 (Box 10)
  - N. & W. Railway Blueprints, 1941 (Box 10)
  - Commonwealth v. Ruscoe, 1941 (Box 10)
  - State Highway v. Marion Investment Corp., 1940-43 (Box 10)
  - U.S. v. Bishop, 1942 (Box 10)
  - Puritan Chemical v. Wolfe's Restaurant, 1941-43 (Box 10)
  - Harris & Graves v. Glade Mountain Corp., 1942 (Box 10)
  - Holston Transportation Co.: Application, 1942 (Box 10)
  - Brooks Equipment v. Bolling, 1942 (Box 10)
  - Porter v. Marion Orange Crush, 1942 (Box 10)
  - Funkhauser v. Ellis, 1942 (Box 10)
  - Cash and Haul Grocery v. Oliver Estate, 1941 (Box 10)
  - Virginia-Lincoln Furniture Corp.: Charter changes, 1936-42 (Box 10)
  - Raymond Williams Judgment, 1934, -40 (Box 10)
  - Town of Chilhowie v. N. & W. Railway, 1937-39 (Box 10)
  - Town of Saltville: 1939-41 Tax Collections, 1941-42 (Box 10)
  - Stone v. N. & W. Railway, 1940-41 (Box 12)
  - H.B. Staley: Wage and hour, 1941 (Box 12)
  - W.A. Stuart: Virginia State Bar Association, 1941 (Box 12)
  - State Highway Department: Saltville, 1936 (Box 12)
  - E.J. Roberts Pardon, 1941 (Box 12)
  - Kroger Grocery & Baking Co.: General file, 1938 (Box 12)
  - Eller v. Hopkins, 1941-42 (Box 12)
  - Bank of Marion v. Lemmon & Wright, 1942 (Box 12)
  - Wolfe's Restaurant, 1941-42, (2 folders) (Box 12)
  - Virginia-Lincoln Furniture Corp.: Car uses of employees, 1934, -40 (Box 12)
  - Whiting Lumber v. Lincoln Builders, 1939 (Box 12)
  - Virginia-Lincoln v. Hendry, 1934 (Box 12)
  - Victory Specialty Co. v. Morris, 1933-34 (Box 12)
  - U.S. Loan Co. v. Spratt, 1938-39 (Box 12)
  - Tannebaum & Son v. Lincoln, 1939 (Box 12)
  - Sussman v. Ross Tavern, 1942 (Box 12)
- Folders Numbered 1-372:
  - C.H. Whiteman, 1933 (Box 12)
  - Wilson, Kemp & Hoggs, 1933, -37 (Box 12)
  - Caldwell Sites, 1934-35 (Box 12)
  - William A. Stuart, 1934-39 (Box 12)
  - A.J. Atwell, 1933-34 (Box 12)
  - Westmoreland Club, 1933-34 (Box 12)
  - W.B. Crockett, 1933 (Box 12)
  - T.W. Ristine, 1933 (Box 12)
  - Henry C. Pruner, 1933 (Box 12)
  - Antone Fisher, 1933 (Box 13)
  - T.B. Ward, 1933 (Box 13)
  - George F. Cook, 1933-34 (Box 13)
  - U.S. Veterans' Bureau, 1933 (Box 13)
  - W.V. Birchfield, 1933-36 (Box 13)
  - Lyman Sevier, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Rice's Filling Station, 1933, -38 (Box 13)
  - John Buchanan, 1933-34 (Box 13)
  - John B. Spires, 1933, -37 (Box 13)
  - Bureau of Vital Statistics, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Bessie Cullop, 1933 (Box 13)
  - A.C. Snider, 1933-34 (Box 13)
  - Fannie Bowser Stewart, 1933, -36 (Box 13)
  - Registrar of Deeds, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Mrs. I.W. White, 1933 (Box 13)
  - William H. Gollehon, 1933, -35 (Box 13)
  - W.B. Crockett, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Helen Reuter Kirk, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Roscoe Russell, 1933 (Box 13)
  - James D. Tate, 1933 (Box 13)
  - E.T.C. Oaks, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Better Housing Institute, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Department of Interior, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Sheriff of Wythe County, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Tom Phillips, 1933 (Box 13)
  - W.P. Chambers, 1933 (Box 13)
  - H. Laurie Smith, 1933 (Box 13)
  - R.L. Suit, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Alec Hutchins, 1926 (Box 13)
  - Meyers & Tabakin, 1933 (Box 13)
  - W.R. Buchanan, 1933 (Box 13)
  - G.P. Cox, 1933 (Box 13)
  - William Tilson, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Collin Webb, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Maggie J. Lyons, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Dr. Don P. Peters, 1934, -38 (Box 13)
  - Baxter Williams, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Fred Rector, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Florence Crabtree Cahill, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Charles E. Wiley, 1934-38 (Box 13)
  - M.N. Moorman, 1933-34 (Box 13)
  - Steve Meek, 1933 (Box 13)
  - John L. Godwin, 1933-34 (Box 13)
  - Marion National Bank, 1934, -38 (Box 13)
  - J.H. Trent, 1933 (Box 13)
  - George M. Seaver, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Mrs. R.M. Gollohon, 1933 (Box 13)
  - W.B. and Margaret Staley, 1935-42 (Box 13)
  - J.F. Tilley, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Fidelity & Deposit Co. of Maryland, 1934-35 (Box 13)
  - W.N. Hayes: Guardian of William A. Hayes, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Tilson Property, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Roderick Butler, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Paul Greever, 1933 (Box 13)
  - J.S. DeJarnette, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Mrs. C.C. Lincoln, 1938 (Box 13)
  - J.F. Ward, 1933-34 (Box 13)
  - Roy J. McAllister, 1933 (Box 13)
  - W.F. Culbert and Sons, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Collins Brothers, 1930-38 (Box 13)
  - Mrs. W.E. Hurt, 1033 (Box 13)
  - Bristol Grocery Co., 1934 (Box 13)
  - George Burchett, 1934 (Box 13)
  - American Bar Association, 1934 (Box 13)
  - Town of Chilhowie, 1934 (Box 13)
  - John Plain & Co., 1933 (Box 14)
  - John B. Huffard, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Interstate Hardware Co., 1934 (Box 14)
  - R.H. Sutherland, 1934 (Box 14)
  - C.G. Dutton, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Vest, 1934 (Box 14)
  - S.M. O'Bannon, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Gordon Snavely, 1934 (Box 14)
  - W.D. Hohenthal, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Alfred Mann, 1933-34 (Box 14)
  - Jake Keller, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Ruth Lewis, 1934 (Box 14)
  - George M. Warren, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Hattie McClanahan, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Mary Gannon Proctor, 1940 (Box 14)
  - James T. Prickett, 1929 (Box 14)
  - George D. Woods, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Mrs. C.D. Carter, 1934 (Box 14)
  - D.M. Cosby, 1933-34 (Box 14)
  - John Lynn Sanders, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Mrs. Harriet Clarke, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Mrs. G.A. Coley, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Ray Rector, 1934-39 (Box 14)
  - Fred Cole, 1934 (Box 14)
  - E.H. Robinson, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Glenn Richardson, 1934 (Box 14)
  - G.J. Walker, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Ira M. Quillen, 1934-39 (Box 14)
  - C.W. House, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Eleanor Preston Watkins, 1934-35 (Box 14)
  - Globe Adjustment Bureau, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Joel W. Flood, 1934 (Box 14)
  - James W. Hutton, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Letscho Deed of Trust, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Jamie Pennington Deed, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Stone Lumber Co., 1934 (Box 14)
  - Haines Wolfe, 1934 (Box 14)
  - R.M. Hale, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Roller Case, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Hobart Martin, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Dr. H.E. Foxworth, 1934 (Box 14)
  - E.B. Sprinkle, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Glenn Mitchell Young, 1934, -36 (Box 14)
  - Virginia Lincoln Furniture, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Tolbert Deed, 1934 (Box 14)
  - R.B. Maxey, 1934 (Box 14)
  - John T. Wassom, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Kelsic Hundley, 1934 (Box 14)
  - C.G. Farris, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Vaught Case, 1934 (Box 14)
  - Arch Graham, 1934 (Box 14)
  - J.N. McAllister, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Rosa Allah Ryan, 1935-36 (Box 14)
  - H. Wise Wheeler, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Wiley Crismond, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Edmund Sheppard, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Piggly Wiggly, 1935, -38 (Box 14)
  - Bruce Thompson, 1934-35 (Box 14)
  - Jannie Bennington, 1931-35 (Box 14)
  - Jessie Hart, 1935 (Box 14)
  - H.L. Atkins, n.d. (Box 14)
  - Max Bronfman, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Mrs. S.E. Cook, 1934-35 (Box 14)
  - Buster Roop, 1935-38 (Box 14)
  - William H. McCarty, 1931-35 (Box 14)
  - Roy Haulsee Deed, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Thomas Carter, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Richard Snider, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Roanoke Linen Supply Inc., 1935-40 (Box 14)
  - Lee Cole, 1935 (Box 14)
  - George M. Atkins, 1941-45 (Box 14)
  - Arthur G. Cress, 1935 (Box 14)
  - T.F. Williams, 1935 (Box 14)
  - York and York, 1935 (Box 14)
  - V.E. (Lonnie) Wolfe, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Martindale Hubbell Inc., 1935 (Box 14)
  - Judge Elben C. Folkes, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Retail Credit Co., 1935 (Box 14)
  - Embrey N. Potts, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Theater Equipment Contract Corp., 1933-35 (Box 14)
  - Percy W. Decker, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Gordon Smith, 1935 (Box 14)
  - [Marion] Town Council, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Charles Young, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Highley & Semans, 1933-35 (Box 14)
  - Mercantile Adjuster, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Retail Credit Co., 1935 (Box 14)
  - Mary Morgan, 1935 (Box 14)
  - , 1935 Thornton to W.B. Todd & Co. (Box 14)
  - E.A. Jones Deed, 1934 (Box 14)
  - R.D. Hankla, 1933-34 (Box 14)
  - American Historical Society, 1934-35 (Box 14)
  - Anderson to Gross Lease, 1935 (Box 14)
  - George Haga, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Repass Deed, 1935 (Box 14)
  - Andrew Simons, 1935-39 (Box 15)
  - Juanita Ford, 1935 (Box 15)
  - Gwyn to Tomlinson, 1934-35 (Box 15)
  - Seaver to Dr. Staley, 1935 (Box 15)
  - Mary Louise Home, 1935 (Box 15)
  - John Q. Rhodes, 1935-39 (Box 15)
  - Walter E. Johnston, 1935-36 (Box 15)
  - Emma Goode, 1935 (Box 15)
  - , 1935 Loyd's of America (Box 15)
  - R.E.M. Goolsby, 1935-37 (Box 15)
  - F.M. Rivinus, 1935 (Box 15)
  - Wheeler Deed, 1935 (Box 15)
  - J.H. Heffinger Will, 1935 (Box 15)
  - Henderson Lease, 1935 (Box 15)
  - Bob Gullion, 1935-36 (Box 15)
  - Marion Handle Mills, 1935 (Box 15)
  - Chilhowie National Bank, 1935 (Box 15)
  - Repass (Atlanta Building & Loan Association), 1935 (Box 15)
  - H.L. Morgan, 1937 (Box 15)
  - Robert Bruce, 1935-36 (Box 15)
  - Fallon Florist, 1936 (Box 15)
  - I.M. Quillen, 1935 (Box 15)
  - R.L. Poore, 1935 (Box 15)
  - Marion Bottling Works, 1936 (Box 15)
  - Charles Edward Lovelace, 1936 (Box 15)
  - Ed Pugh, 1936 (Box 15)
  - W.P. Richardson, 1940, -43 (Box 15)
  - Accounts paid, 1936-40 (Box 15)
  - Virginia Auto Mutual Insurance Co., 1936 (Box 15)
  - T.F. Cox License Application [for operating a bus line] (see also Box 16), 1936-42 (Box 15)
  - Williamson Deed, 1936 (Box 15)
  - Recommendations, 1939, -41 (Box 15)
  - H.W. Bowers: Deed of Trust, 1936 (Box 15)
  - A.B. Roberts, 1936 (Box 15)
  - William M. Tuck, 1937 (Box 15)
  - Collins Permit, 1936 (Box 15)
  - Deeds, 1924, 1937-41 (Box 15)
  - D.D. Hull, 1936 (Box 15)
  - Ralph Killinger, 1936 (Box 15)
  - E.V. Greever, 1937 (Box 15)
  - C.S. Wassum, 1935-37 (Box 15)
  - Edward G. Borjes, 1937 (Box 15)
  - Marion Drug Co., 1937 (Box 15)
  - Contracts, 1937-41 (Box 15)
  - Janie Anderson Bane, 1937-38 (Box 15)
  - Martha B. Hackler, 1927, -37 (Box 15)
  - Booth Will, 1937 (Box 15)
  - Lettie and Gary Snider Will, 1937 (Box 15)
  - Miriam Sheffey, 1937 (Box 15)
  - G.C. Musser, 1937 (Box 15)
  - Robinson Will, 1937 (Box 15)
  - Lease Agreements, 1938 (Box 15)
  - Julia Parker, 1938 (Box 15)
  - Helen Murphy, 1938 (Box 16)
  - Mrs. B.H. Conner, 1938-40 (Box 16)
  - Lena and Paul Kelly, 1938 (Box 16)
  - Hickey, McCorkle, Hackney, 1938-39 (Box 16)
  - Mrs. John Wilkinson, 1938 (Box 16)
  - Women's Missionary Union of Virginia, 1936, -38 (Box 16)
  - Lynn and Brainerd Adams, 1939 (Box 16)
  - W.M. Sclater, 1939 (Box 16)
  - Clay Church, 1939 (Box 16)
  - Orange Crush Bottling Co., 1939 (Box 16)
  - Cloyd Martin, 1939 (Box 16)
  - J. Cochran Copenhaver Will, 1941 (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous, 1938-39 (Box 16)
  - Wills [Duplicates?], 1941 (Box 16)
  - M.C. Richard Will, 1942 (Box 16)
  - Mountain Bus Lines (see also Box 15), 1933-48 (Box 16)
- Unnumbered Files
  Arrangement
  Now alphabetized.
  - Abbitt v. Collins [H.L. Moorman Estate], 1932-33 (Box 16)
  - Appalachian Electric Power Co.: General file, 1938-42 (Box 16)
  - Charles Atherton, 1934 (Box 16)
  - Atkins v. U.S., 1941-44 (Box 16)
  - Atkins v. U.S.: Blueprint, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous A, 1949 (Box 16)
  - Robert P. Beaman, 1943 (Box 16)
  - Blakemore v. Saunders, 1943 (Box 16)